Register of the Leland Barrows papers, 1942-1987
Hoover Institution Archives
- CAREER FILE, 1948-1987 (Boxes 3-14)
  - United States Department of Agriculture, correspondence (Box-folder 12: 8)
  - United States Department of Commerce (see: General/International Trade)
  - United States Department of State (see also: Research Analysis Corporation (RAC))
    - General (Box-folder 12: 9)
    - Agreements (Box-folder 12: 10)
    - Circulars (Box-folder 12: 11)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 12: 12)
    - Directory (Box-folder 12: 13)
    - Financial records (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - Lists (Box-folder 13: 2)
    - Memoranda (Box-folder 13: 3)
    - Messages (Box-folder 13: 4)
    - Military passes (Box-folder 13: 5)
    - Outlines (Box-folder 13: 6)
    - Programs (Box-folder 13: 7)
    - Reports (Box-folder 13: 8-9)
      Includes related material.
    - Statements (Box-folder 13: 10)
    - Study (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - Telegrams (Box-folder 14: 2)
    - Work plans (Box-folder 14: 3)
    - Miscellany (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - United States Department of Transportation
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - Reports (Box-folder 14: 6)
  - United States, President's Task Force on International Development, memoranda (see also: SUBJECT FILE) (Box-folder 14: 7)
  - United States War Relocation Authority, correspondence (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - University of Pittsburgh (see also: CORRESPONDENCE and SUBJECT FILE)
    - General
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 14: 9-10)
      - Memoranda (Box-folder 14: 11)
      - Newsletters (Box-folder 14: 12)
      - Reports (Box-folder 14: 13)
    - Development Institute for AID Mid-Career Officers (DIAMCO)
      - General (Box-folder 14: 14)
      - Handbook (Box-folder 14: 15)
      - Lecture notes (Box-folder 14: 16)
  - Washington Technical Institute
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 14: 17)
    - Memoranda (Box-folder 14: 18)
    - Miscellany (Box-folder 14: 19)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1965-1976 (Boxes 15-25)
  Articles, brochures, clippings, comments, maps, organizational records, reports, testimony, and miscellany relating to various organizations and countries, arranged alphabetically by subject. See also: CAREER FILE.
  - Africa
    - General (Box-folder 15: 1-5)
    - Chad (Box-folder 15: 6-7)
    - Liberia (Box-folder 15: 8)
    - Mauritania (Box-folder 15: 9)
    - Nigeria (Box-folder 15: 10-16)
    - Rhodesia (Box-folder 15: 17-18)
    - South Africa (Box-folder 15: 19-21)
    - South Africa (Box-folder 16: 1-5)
  - Asian-American Educational Exchange, Inc. (Box-folder 16: 6)
  - Australia (Box-folder 16: 7)
  - Bangladesh (Box-folder 16: 8)
  - Canada (Box-folder 16: 9)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace (Box-folder 16: 10)
  - Conference on Economic Cooperation (1975: Paris, France) (Box-folder 16: 11)
  - Conference on the United Nations of the Next Decade (1974: Vail, Colorado) (Box-folder 16: 12)
  - Developing countries, economic conditions (Box-folder 16: 13)
  - Greece (Box-folder 16: 14-15)
  - India (Box-folder 16: 16-17)
  - Inter-American Investment Development Center (Box-folder 16: 18)
  - International agencies (Box-folder 16: 19)
  - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (Box-folder 16: 20-21)
  - International relief, commonwealth countries (Box-folder 16: 22)
  - National Academy of Public Administration (Box-folder 17: 1-5)
  - National Academy of Public Administration (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - Turkey (Box-folder 18: 2)
  - United Nations Conference on Trade and Development (UNCTAD) (Box-folder 18: 3-17)
  - United States, foreign policy (Box-folder 18: 18)
  - United States, American Revolution Bicentennial Commission (Box-folder 18: 19)
  - United States Department of Agriculture (Box-folder 18: 20-21)
  - United States Department of Commerce (Box-folder 19: 1-10)
  - United States Department of State (Box-folder 19: 11-13)
  - United States Department of State (Box-folder 20: 1-25)
  - United States Department of State (Box-folder 21: 1-5)
  - United States Department of Transportation (Box-folder 21: 6-10)
  - United States Indian Affairs Bureau (Box-folder 21: 11-13)
  - United States, President's Task Force on International Development (see also: CAREER FILE/Research Analysis Corporation) (Box-folder 21: 14-19)
  - United States, President's Task Force on International Development (Box-folder 22: 1-9)
  - United States, President's Task Force on International Development (Box-folder 23: 1-14)
  - United States Advisory Commission on International Educational and Cultural Affairs (Box-folder 23: 15)
  - Vietnam (see also: United States, foreign policy) (Box-folder 23: 16-19)
  - Vietnam (Box-folder 24: 1-15)
  - Vietnam (Box-folder 25: 1-11)
  - White House Conference on Education (1975: United States) (Box-folder 25: 12)
  - Miscellany (Box-folder 25: 13)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1942-1955 (Box 26)
  14 prints depicting Leland Barrows, Dwight D. Eisenhower, and Phan-Tat-Thanh, the organizational structure of the U.S. Department of Agriculture, and railway tracks and trains in Cameroon.
  - 2 photographs of Phan-Tat-Thanh holding a personal letter from Dwight D. Eisenhower, including one with Leland Barrows, Director, United States Operations Mission (USOM), and one showing a photograph of the President on the wall, undated (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - 2 photographs of Phan-Tat-Thanh with the statuette of La Dong Tan, including one with Leland Barrows, and one of the letter from Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1955 (Box-folder 26: 2)
  - 1 photograph depicting the organizational structure of the U.S. Department of Agriculture for the war effort, 1942 (Box-folder 26: 3)
  - 9 photographs of railway tracks and trains in Cameroon, undated (Box-folder 26: 4)
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1968 (Box 27, Map case)
  Map of the United States, sample letter of introduction, and transparencies and related texts used for overhead projector, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Sample letter of introduction for an ambassador, undated (Box 27)
  - Transparencies and related text used for overhead projector for presentation on U.S. assistance programs in South Vietnam, undated
  - Map of the United States, indicating areas qualified for full financial assistance and grants, issued by the Economic Development Administration of the U.S. Department of Commerce, 1968 (Map case)
- DECLASSIFIED U.S. GOVERNMENT RECORDS, 1969-1970 (Box 26)
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Includes some interfiled, unclassified government records. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover, thereunder chronologically by date of creation.
  - 2016 February release of records, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 26: 5-12)
    Reports, memoranda, and correspondence relating to Vietnam, particularly from an aid/economic perspective, that appear to be from Barrow's work with the Research Analysis Corporation (RAC).